



# **Resume Summary**

Since my first work experience 13 years ago as a civil engineer and entrepreneur, I have always been passionate about the world of computers and software.

One year ago, I realized my dream of becoming a Full-Stack web developer through self-learning. Finally, after hundreds of thousands of lines of code, I successfully achieved the FullStack Javascript Bootcamp.

I am looking for the perfect setting for developing my skills as a team leader, commitment, responsibility, and pro-activity, always focused on the common interest above the individual.



# **Experience**

Nov 2021 -Jan-2022

### **Bootcamp Assistant (TA)**

Henry

- Coordinate a group of students to achieve integration to the study group.
- Guide students in the first steps of the course.
- Assist to solve exercises and promote group collaboration (Pair Programming).
- Suggest ideas to improve the Bootcamp processes.

Nov 2021 -Present

## Freelance Developer

**Papermud** 

- Develop a POC web application for a startup using PHP, Laravel, Bootstrap 5, MySQL and Git. (Frontend and backend).
- Design the UI and apply UX knowledge.
- Deploy the app on the client server.

Jan 2021 -Present

### Founder - Developer

**Entrepreneur** 

- Develop several personal affiliate marketing websites using PHP, WordPress, CSS, HTML, Javascript.
- Develop a (Saas) web app as entrepreneurship to meet the administrative requirements of small medical offices.
   (Reservations, Patients, Medical history, Payments, etc.), in addition to offering health professionals an online presence with their website

Stack: TALL (Tailwind CSS, Alpine JS, Laravel, Livewire)

2008 - 2020

## Early days as civil engineer...

- Agata Project Manager
- Elements Studio Founder Project Manager
- LatinoAmericana de contrucción LATCO Project Manager
- AR Construcciones Project Manager
- Constructora Conconcreto Resident Engineer

### **Achievements:**

Projects planning

Execution and lidership of projects on time and under budget



## **Contact / Personal info**

### **Address**

Mexico City

#### Phone

(+52) 55 4403 5909

### E-mail

ramalejandro@gmail.com

### **Github**

alejodelosrios

### LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/manuel-alejandro-ramírez



## **Technologies / Skills**

Decision making React - Redux - Typescript
Planning PHP - Laravel - Livewire
Teamwork Html - CSS - Javascript
Proactivity Node JS - Express JS
Leadership Sequelize - PostgreSQL -

Bootstrap - Tailwind CSS



Fast learning

## **Tools / Software**

Vim PhotoShop
Insomnia - Postman Responsively APP
Tower (Git) Figma
TablePlus - Beekeeper Advance MS Excel
Notion AutoCAD
Slack ArchiCad



### **Education**

FullStack Web development Bootcamp Oct 2021 - Feb 2022 Henry

+800 hours of programming using Html, CSS, CSS Preprocessors Javascript, React JS, Redux, Node JS, Express, Sequelize, and PostgreSQL

Daily pair-programming meetings
Development of individual and group projects.

**Civil Engineer Bachelor's Degree** 2003 - 2009 Universidad Nacional de Colombia



# **Courses / Certifications**

Master en PHP, SQL, POO, MVC, Laravel, WordPress
Udemy
Aprende a crear una API rest con Laravel
Udemy
Excel Macros
Universidad Nacional de Colombia
Microsoft Project
2007



# Languages

Constructora Conconcreto

Spanish Native ●●●●●
English Intermediate ●●●●●